Kontakt

hello@carlosengels.com

www.linkedin.com/in/cloudsolutions-carlos (LinkedIn) github.com/carlosengels (Personal)

Top-Kenntnisse

Python (Programming Language)
Databases
Server Architecture

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
French (Professional Working)
German (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
Ausbildung zum Musikproduzenten
Create Python Linux Script to
Generate a Disk Usage Report
Radio RA2
Command Line in Linux

Carlos Engels

Site Reliability Engineer | AWS & Kubernetes | Terraform | CI/CD with GitLab | Driving Resilient Cloud Infrastructure & Automation Arvada, Colorado, Vereinigte Staaten von Amerika

Zusammenfassung

Hi there

Check out my personal projects Kanban: https://github.com/users/carlosengels/projects/1/views/1

I'm a Backend Developer with experience in software development, AWS implementation, deployment and configuration.

I've worked in a helpdesk environment which serviced clients globally and I was able to perfect solving problems, one ticket at a time. With my problem-solving mindset and software development skills I identify and address complex business challenges such as scaling support for applications. Now I've embarked on the software development journey with the goal to help organizations scale their operations reliably.

As the world has become more technologically interconnected and vulnerable I want to bring my passion for threat mitigation to my future employer. By leveraging the experience that I gained through the CompTIA Security+ certification and my personal CLI port scanner project I will bring security awareness to my next development role.

SKILLS & ABILITIES:

- ## Java Software Engineering
- # Development and Deployment of AWS solutions
- # Network and Application Security
- # Threat and Vulnerability awareness training
- # Application Support
- # Systems Troubleshooting
- # Technical Writing

Berufserfahrung

Vertafore
Site Reliability Engineer
April 2023 - Present (2 Jahre 1 Monat)
Denver, Colorado, United States

Twilio

Audiovisual/IT Services Engineer Oktober 2021 - Oktober 2022 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)

Denver, Colorado, United States

- Deployed and maintained our Denver office AV systems
- Provided remote technical support for wide array of Zoom issues
- Created documentation for users and other Zoom admins
- Supported company-wide Zoom webinar events

Astreya

4 Jahre

Audiovisual Services Regional Lead @Google, AMER April 2019 - Oktober 2021 (2 Jahre 7 Monate) Boulder, Colorado

- Problem Management Services for the Global AV fleet
- Identify and surface bugs to AV Meet SWE & hardware team
- Regional oversight of operations
- Technical escalation point for L2 technicians
- Create, update and present training materials (including SOPs) for L1/L2 technicians

Audiovisual Services Coordinator @Google, AMER Dezember 2018 - April 2019 (5 Monate) Boulder, Colorado

- Triaging & dispatching of service requests, based on technicians availability and existing workload
- Maintenance and development of departmental workflow & operation procedures, such as improved global ticket routing strategies which can be easily scaled up.

Audiovisual Services Engineer @Google, Boulder Campuses November 2017 - November 2018 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)

Boulder, Colorado

- On-site and remote AV troubleshooting:
- Videoconferencing systems (Google Meet, formerly Hangouts)
- Multizone Crestron systems
- UX Labs
- White-glove AV event support
- Installation, commissioning and decommissioning of AV equipment. This included Crestron, Biamb, QSC and Google proprietary hardware.

Sound Performance

AV and Home Automation Technician

September 2016 - Oktober 2017 (1 Jahr 2 Monate)

Coral Gables, Florida

Installation and maintenance service for residential and commercial multi-zone AV-networks:

- Development of AutoCAD drawings based on BOMs created in D-Tools SI
- Installation and programming of Lutron lighting and shading products.
- Installation and troubleshooting service for JBL, K-Array, SoundTube & Ashly systems
- Prewiring, on/off-site rack-building, hardware customizations & equipment delivery

Ravinia's Steans Music Institute Production Coordinator Internship Mai 2016 - September 2016 (5 Monate)

Highland Park, Illinois

- Organized and executed audio/video recordings and livestreams of concerts and rehearsals
- Provided stage management, including attending of reherasals to note stage details a
- Created and distributed concert program inserts
- Coordinated artist transportation, meals and housing
- Responded to, logged, and prioritize artist requests & general office administrative work
- Maintained building tidiness

Levine Events

Events Technology Manager

September 2015 - September 2016 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)

Page 3 of 4

Hollywood, Florida

- Met with stakeholders for high-profile events to determine technology needs
- Supervised vendors and contractors in order ensure delivery of services
- Coordinated deployment of equipment from central warehouse to multiple simultaneous events across south Florida
- Managed equipment inventory
- Deployed and operated equipment during events

Ministry Recording Group Assistant Recording Engineer Januar 2016 - April 2016 (4 Monate)

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

- Edited and prepared of Pro Tools projects for studio mixing sessions.
- Operated an SSL9000J and Pro Tools HD system at Circle House and The Hit Factory Miami

Berlin Music Week
Stage Manager
September 2013 - September 2014 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)
Postbahnhof, Berlin

The conference, including VUT Indie Days, will deal with issues in recorded music, interactive, tech & startups. The event will focus on new players and offer a look ahead for the digital transformation. Besides becoming an exchange of creativity, panels, matchmakings and workshops in 2014 gave around 3,500 trade professionals from 30 countries the chance to be inspired and to inspire others.

Ausbildung

BloomTech

Bootcamp Certification, Backend Developement · (Oktober 2022 - April 2023)

SAE Institute Germany

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Audio Production · (2013 - 2015)

Deutsche POP Berlin

Music Production Degree, Musikproduktion · (2011 - 2012)